Today we are going to try this hand-made mochi (rice cake)
small place though
Please pick up yourself for eat-in
oh blast
I struggle every time when I read the menu
because you don't know which one should you order
and how big one portion is
but to my great joy, not this time
photo for reference only
three mochi, peanut stuffing
and one shaved ice
OK, please wait a sec
OK
three with peanut stuffing
three plain ones, 6 in total
do you wish to start with plain ones? if so i can make them for you now
then prepare the shaved ice
since plain ones can not hold that long
ok, i see. then i'll have plain ones first
so plain ones don't hold long, right?
yes
why?
- It will become less crispy
- Have a bit and you will see why
Ones with peanut stuffing don't have this problem
they can wait
here you are
You can go upstairs now
I will bring you the shaved ice
OK, maybe I should pay now
12, plus 12
I am gonna go upstairs and have this now
Thanks!
roasted soybean powder
so what i have in my hand is plain hand-made mochi
it is of the shape of a spindle
from the moment I come here, until now I have the mochi in my had
i was surrounded all the time being by the smell of roast soybean powder
it is made with glutinous rice dough
stuffed with fried crisp
then covered with soybean powder
Thanks
the bits on the surface are warm
you can eat the warm bits at the same time with the ice
more ice, yes, ice are below
what is this?
Adazi (tapioca cube)
you can also find taros under
you mean taro puree?
no. real taro
cool, thanks
be careful when you go downstairs
feel so warm
adazi is warm
combined with the cold ice
both in your mouth
Adazi has a texture similar to gummy candy
the girl mentioned taro below ice
watch me turning up the iceberg, and see if we can find taro
Ever since I arrived in Quanzhou, i found there are so many snacks made of taros
desserts made of taros
not over sweet
it's taro, right?
the rice cake is made of glutinous rice
very soft and firm outside
but the fried fillings are very crispy
totally different textures
reacting harmoniously in your mouth
How did you come up with this idea of making mochi?
It's actually a specialty of Zhangzhou
i went there a few years ago and tried it
the first impression was wow so delicious
but i did not give too much thought to it
because i worked as employee
then i went there again
every time i talked with my girl about Zhangzhou we thought of the mochi
so when i went there to eat it again, we were saying: well we don't have it in Quanzhou, so we introduced it to Quanzhou